etihad.com 2017-12-10

# Privacy Policy - Etihad Airways

### Flight and Booking Information

### Flight and Booking Information

If you use the Etihad Websites to make a flight booking or manage a reservation, we will collect and use information about you as necessary to manage the booking. This may include personal information such as your name, gender, date of birth and passport details, any meal preferences or frequent flyer programme membership references (if applicable) together with payment details and contact information (such as phone number and e-mail address) for the lead passenger.

If you or any passenger travelling has special health, dietary or access requirements, which you or they would like us to be aware of, we may collect information about these matters where this is provided.

Where you are making a booking on behalf of other travelling passengers, it is your responsibility to represent that passenger in the booking process and explain how we will use their personal information as set out in this Privacy Policy. You must obtain their consent to make the booking and share their details with us as anticipated by this Privacy Policy. We will assume that you have done this.

### Advanced Passenger Information

### Advanced Passenger Information

On some routes we are required to pass details of the itinerary and booking details in our Passenger Name Record system to border control, customs and law enforcement officers at ports of entry / exit on your itinerary. This currently includes all flights through an airport in Australia, Canada, France, UK or USA. We will share this information with relevant authorities as required and permitted by local and applicable laws. For more information on these requirements please click [here](http://www.dhs.gov/xlibrary/assets/privacy/privacy_stmt_pnr.pdf).

Etihad may also collect personal data, including information regarding criminal records, in order to reduce the risk of terrorism and to comply with security measures.

If you are in, or flying to/from France, please note that in accordance with Article L 237 -7 of French Internal Security Code, air carriers may transmit reservation data collected from their passengers (PNR) to the French national public services and competent authorities for the purposes and under conditions as defined in the Decret N° 2014-1095 dated 26/09/2014.

### Etihad Guest Frequent Flyer Programme 

### Etihad Guest Frequent Flyer Programme 

If you join our frequent flyer programme, Etihad Guest, you will be asked to register your personal details with Etihad Guest. This will allow Etihad Guest to manage your account and provide you with rewards and benefits.

When you join Etihad Guest you will be asked to confirm that you agree to share data between Etihad and Etihad Guest to receive these benefits. Any information shared with Etihad Guest is held subject to Etihad Guest's separate [ **p** **rivacy policy**](http://www.etihadguest.com/en/privacy-policy/) and [ **terms and conditions**](http://www.etihadguest.com/en/terms-and-conditions/).

### Customer support and online services

### Customer support and online services

If you contact us with a query or comment about any of our services, or would like us to keep you informed about latest news and developments at Etihad, we will need to collect information about you (including your contact details) to help us respond to your query or request. We may do this when you call our customer support centre, or interact with us through our online support tools.

We may also keep a record of any communications we have with you (including a recording of any calls you make). We do this in compliance with applicable laws to help monitor and improve the quality of our customer support services. Where you have asked to receive an information update from us, you are free to change your preferences (for more information, refer to 'Updating your personal profile and preferences' section below).

### Online profile

### Online profile

If you have registered a personal profile on one of the Etihad Websites, we may ask you to provide additional information about your lifestyle, interests and family background. This information helps us to provide a more personalized service to you. 

### Events and promotions

### Events and promotions

From time to time we hold events and special promotions to introduce Etihad to new customers. If you come to one of these events, or take part in a promotion, we may ask for your personal details to help us run the promotion and keep in touch with you about our services and any special offers that we think may be of interest. Any information, which you provide, will be used in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy and you can unsubscribe from further communications from us at any time (for more information, refer to 'Updating your personal profile and preferences' section below). 

### Obligatory data collection

### Obligatory data collection

When you make a flight booking with us we will process Flight and Booking Information and Advanced Passenger Information as described above. If you decline to provide this information to us, or provide us with incomplete or inaccurate information, we will not be able to complete your requested travel reservation(s).

The Etihad Guest Frequent Flyer Programme, Customer Support and Online Services, Online Profile and Events and Promotions are optional features of our service and we will only process information about you in relation to these services if you actively participate in these feature offerings. Whilst you are free to limit the amount of personal information provided to us in relation to these services, you need to be aware that certain features may be restricted or disabled if full information is not provided. 

### How we use personal information

### How we use personal information

We will hold, store and use personal information (which will be processed with/by electronic and non-electronic means) in the following ways:

  * To fulfil any agreement we have with you, including to process your flight, send your itinerary, or contact you if there is a problem with your reservation;
  * To allow you to register on the Etihad Websites and administer and personalize any of the online services which you have asked us to provide to you;
  * To keep you (with your permission)  informed about our products and services and those of our preferred partners where we think you will find this valuable (subject to your right to opt-out, which you can exercise by clicking here);
  * To allow you to take part in any contest or other promotional offers you have asked to participate in;
  * To analyse how our users access and navigate our services and use of the Etihad Websites;
  * To get feedback from customers on the quality of our services - we may invite you to participate in questionnaires or surveys;
  * To help detect and prevent criminal activity; and
  * For any other purpose notified on the relevant Etihad Website.

·        To keep you (with your permission)  informed about our products and services and those of our preferred partners where we think you will find this valuable ~~~~  (subject to your right to opt-out, which you can exercise by clicking here);

### How we share information with others

### How we share information with others

We work closely with a number of trusted partners with whom we need to share personal information to help us provide our services. These include:

  * Our group companies around the world, including other Etihad brands such as Etihad Cargo, Etihad Holidays and Etihad Guest;
  * Partner airlines where you are travelling on a booking which involves a codeshare;
  * Frequent flyer and other reward and partner programmes with whom you have asked us to share your details;
  * Banks and payment providers, to authorize and complete payments;
  * Service providers who work with us to help provide our services, including local agents who help manage customer needs at airports or operate our limousine service, and contractors who help us run our office operations;
  * Companies to whom we transfer or may transfer our rights and duties under our agreement with you;
  * Customs and/or immigration departments or other regulatory authorities;
  * Other agencies, law enforcement or governmental organisations where we are required to so by any applicable law; or
  * Our contractors and other third party agents outside of the Etihad Airways Group for any of the above or to send you marketing information on our behalf.

Please note that some of these data recipients may be based in territories such as the United Arab Emirates or the United States of America, whose laws do not offer, in the opinion of the European Commission or the Director of the Spanish Data Protection Agency, an adequate level of data protection.

If you would like to know more about who we share your personal information with please click here or write to the Ethics and Compliance Office, Etihad Airways, PO Box 35566, Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates.

### How we protect your information

### How we protect your information

We invest significant resources in protecting the security and confidentiality of personal information.

  * We offer the use of secure communication transmission software (known as "secure sockets layer" or "SSL") that encrypts all information you input to our website before it is sent to us. SSL is an industry standard encryption protocol and this ensures that the information is reasonably protected against unauthorised interception;
  * We also follow strict security procedures in the storage and disclosure of information which you have given us, to prevent unauthorised access to that information; and
  * We take all reasonable steps to protect your personal information but cannot guarantee the security of any data you disclose to us via email or online.
  * Where you disclose information to us using our mobile app, please ensure that your device remains safe. We cannot be held responsible for any data misuse arising from unauthorised access to your device.

### Collecting data from your mobile device

### Collecting data from your mobile device

  * Our mobile app may access device information or data from your mobile device. Information is only accessed to provide the services you choose from us. 
  * If you would like to restrict our collection of your data, please adjust the settings on your device. In particular, if you would like to restrict our access to your location, please turn off location data collection in your device’s settings. If you do decide to turn off location information, please note that services such as airport mapping, city code search and other location-based notifications on your day of travel will not work. 
  * Please note that our app will activate the camera on your device, if you choose to use the credit card or passport scanning functions. You can prevent this by not using those features.

### More about direct marketing

### More about direct marketing

We are committed to keeping you informed about our products and services in line with your personal preferences. We will always ask your permission before sending marketing material, whether about our services of those or our preferred partners. 

We will usually send this by email but we may choose to contact you in other ways for example by phone, post, SMS and/or other electronic means if that is more appropriate. You can ask us to stop sending you marketing material at any time by **contacting us** or changing your marketing preferences within your personal profile (see below).

### Updating your personal profile and preferences

### Updating your personal profile and preferences

At any time you can update or correct your personal profile, or change your preferences for the way in which you would like us to communicate with you - including how you receive news updates from us, or details of our latest offers.

If you have an online account, the easiest way to do this is by logging into your account and changing your personal details. You can also click the "unsubscribe" link that you will find on any online newsletters which you receive, or contact our customer support team by email ( **click here** ).

### Accessing your personal information

### Accessing your personal information

In some countries, you have the right to see or access the personal information we hold about you. We may charge a small fee for processing this request (where permitted by law). To receive a copy, please write to the Ethics and Compliance Office, Etihad Airways, PO Box 35566, Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates or click here to send your request via the web. 

If you are concerned that any of the information we hold about you is incorrect, out of date or may be used inappropriately, please click here or write to the address above to report  your concerns and we will take appropriate steps to amend our records. These arrangements are without prejudice to any statutory rights you may have in your country to require us to rectify, cease processing and / or delete certain records, or enforce privacy rights before a local data protection supervisory authority.

If you are in Spain, please note that you can exercise your rights to cancel our processing of your data, and to object to the processing of data, by any company in the Etihad Group, free of charge.

### Transfer of your personal information

### Transfer of your personal information

We need to transfer the personal information referred to in this policy across the Etihad group of companies to help operate our business efficiently. We also allow third party service providers to process personal information where this is needed in connection with a service they provide to us. These arrangements may involve your personal information being located in various countries around the world. The countries to which we commonly disclose your personal information include the UAE, where we have our head offices, the US, UK and the countries where you are flying to and from. Some of these countries, for example, the US and the UAE, may not have data protection laws that provide an equivalent level of data privacy protection as the laws in your country of residence. 

When in these countries, your personal information may, where legally permitted,  be disclosed as required by applicable law. This may include providing access to foreign courts or governmental authorities but we will only do this where we are legally obligated and permitted to do so.

We will always strive to adopt the highest standards of privacy protection, wherever your personal information is located and adopt appropriate measures (consistent with locally applicable privacy laws) to secure an adequate level of privacy protection.  

### Retaining your personal information 

### Retaining your personal information 

We keep records for as long as required to manage bookings and provide the other relevant services anticipated by this Privacy Policy. Where your information is no longer required, we will ensure it is disposed of in a safe manner.

### Updates

### Updates

We keep this Privacy Policy under regular review and place updates on the Etihad Websites from time to time. Please review this Privacy Policy periodically for changes. Your continued use of our website or services once you have been notified of the revised Privacy Policy constitutes your acceptance of it.

### Our policy on "cookies"

### Our policy on "cookies"

A cookie is an element of data that a website sends to your browser, which then stores it on your system. Cookies may collect personal information about you. Cookies allow us to understand who has seen which pages and advertisements, to determine how frequently particular pages are visited and to determine the most popular areas of our website. Cookies also allow us to make Etihad Websites more user-friendly by, for example, allowing us to take you to the language site of last use, so that we can give you a better experience when you return to our website.

A cookie will be deployed on your device when you visit Etihad Websites unless you indicate that you do not wish this to happen or if you have turned this feature 'off' in your web browser settings.

For more information about how our cookies work and information about how to manage your cookie settings please visit our **Cookie Policy**.

### Other websites

### Other websites

Etihad Websites may link you to other websites. We are not responsible for the way in which third party websites operate or the way in which they may process any personal information, which you provide to them. It is important that you understand this and check their respective privacy policies and terms of use.

### Privacy concerns

### Privacy concerns

Please click here or write to the Ethics and Compliance Office, Etihad Airways, PO Box 35566, Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates if you have any concerns about our compliance with applicable privacy laws or this Privacy Policy. We will endeavour to respond to your concerns as soon as possible and we may make seek further information from you in order to provide a full and complete response. In some countries, you may have rights to raise the matter with a relevant data protection authority or ombudsman.

### Recruitment Fraud

### Recruitment Fraud

We are aware of some people and organisations, unrelated to the Etihad Airways Group of Companies, sending emails or otherwise contacting people to make fraudulent offers of employment. These people and organisations may request personal information or money from you in order to progress the application. We would strongly advise you never to provide your bank account or credit card details as part of an employment application.

During our recruitment process you will always be asked to meet face-to-face with a  representative of the Etihad Airways Group of Companies for an interview before any formal offer of employment is made. More information on our recruitment process may be found [here](https://careers.etihad.com/).

No member of the Etihad Airways Group of Companies will ever ask for payment of any kind, including money transfers, from job applicants. We will never ask for advance payment from you for travel expenses or visas/work permits if your application is successful. 

**If you are asked for money in order to process or take up a job opportunity with us please treat it as fraudulent and** **contact us** **immediately.**
